Guide to the Mark Kulstad Academic Papers, 1971-2015 UA 385
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series V: Research, 1978-2007 (Box 21-23)
  - Grants, Reserves, and Publishers, 1978-2007 (Box 21-22)
    - Revisions and drafts (Box 22-23)
      - Expression book incomplete (Box 22, Folder 15)
      - Expression book, 1991 (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - Expression thesis (Box 23, Folder 2)
      - Extra (partial copy of page proofs of consc.book) (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - Expression paper (Box 23, Folder 4)
      - Garland series Reprinting, 1989-01-10 (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - Greg Brown Compossibility + Perfection (Box 23, Folder 6)
      - Lcsa Documents ( + David's Instrsi) (Box 23, Folder 7)
      - "Did Leibniz Incline toward Monistic Pantheism?" (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - Leibniz's Conception of Expression (Box 23, Folder 9,10)
      - Leibniz + Spinoza time for a new look? 502 paper version submitted to JHP, 1995-02-26 (Box 23, Folder 11)
      - Leibniz on pre-established harmony (Box 23, Folder 12)
      - VI. Leibniz and Europa (Box 23, Folder 13)
      - Leibniz on Consciousness and Reflection: The Early Years and the Late Years Nicholas Jolley (Box 23, Folder 14)
      - Leibniz writings (Box 23, Folder 15)
      - Madison conference paper (Box 23, Folder 16)
      - Mercer commentary Portland APA, 1988 (Box 23, Folder 17)
      - On Leibniz's "Mature Philosophy and the Discourse on Metaphysics" Spain Version, 1989-12-26 (Box 23, Folder 18)
      - On Leibniz's "Mature Philsophy" and the Discourse on Metaphysics", 1982-1983 (Box 23, Folder 19)
      - Pantheism (congress paper) (Box 23, Folder 20)
      - Phil 502 papers (Fall) Proofs for HPQ, Spinoza Vol 13 no.3 article, 1995-1996 (Box 23, Folder 21)
      - Review Jolley's book (Box 23, Folder 22)
      - Review Dascal's book (Box 23, Folder 23)
      - Rice University Studies (Box 23, Folder 24)
      - Schepers-Festschrift, 1989-01-03 (Box 23, Folder 25)
      - Schepers Festschrift Apperception (Box 23, Folder 26)
      - Shorter Lucas + Grint Paper (what was sent to APA) (Box 23, Folder 27)
      - Sleigh's Book: Refree's report (Box 23, Folder 28)
      - Some Difficulties in Leibniz's definition of perception (Box 23, Folder 29)
      - The Southern Journal of Philosophy volume xviii number 4 (Box 23, Folder 30)
      - Southwestern Philosophical Society "Frankfurt's Interpretation of Descartes Validation of Reason" (Box 23, Folder 31)
      - The Southwest Journal of Philsophy (Box 23, Folder 32)
      - Spanish version Leibniz (Box 23, Folder 33)
      - Spimoni paper, HPQ, 1995 (Box 23, Folder 34)
      - Spimoni talk, Including Lynx paper (Box 23, Folder 35)
      - Spimoni transcript (Box 23, Folder 36)
      - Spinoza's demonstation of Monism: A New Line Defense, 1995-02-27 (Box 23, Folder 37)
      - Version of Lucas + Grint paper sent to Spain, 1989-12-26 (Box 23, Folder 38)
      - Victoria's index for expression book (Box 23, Folder 39)
  - Leibniz and Spinoza Research, 1993-1995 (Box 23)
    - Spinoza + Leibniz Articles Summer, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 40)
    - Leibniz + Spinoza (including readings): chief research supplements (Box 23, Folder 41)
    - Leibniz et les puissances du language (Box 23, Folder 42)
    - Computer theorm proving Spinoza (Box 23, Folder 43)
    - Reginald O. Savage Leibniz + Counterfactual (Box 23, Folder 44)
    - France- Cerisy- La- Salle Includes Cerisy + official letters ( concha letters moved to (Box 23, Folder 45)
      Related Materials
      There are Photos in this file (9)
    - France paper, handout + translation Cerisy La Salle, 1995-06-16 (Box 23, Folder 46)
    - Galley + summary/ Locke paper (Box 23, Folder 47)
- Series VI: Publications and Finished Drafts, 1977-2009 (Box 24)
  - American Catholic Philosophical Quarterly (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Leibniz Animals and Apperception (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Apeticion Y Principios En La Filosofia De Leibniz (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Appetition in the Philosophy of Leibniz (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Appetition and Principles in Leibniz's philosophy (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Apperception in Leibniz's Principle of Nature and Grace (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Causation in Early Modern Philosophy (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Causation and Preestablished Harmony in the Early Development of Leibniz's Philosophy (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Cerisy La Salle Whence Variety? (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Concha Roldan(includes correspondence) Kulstad, Roads Not Taken with Curtis Hs editorial files, 1995-11-04 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Colored Sheet Leibniz Sptsch Mercer + Kulstad handouts APA, 1998-12-29 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Did Leibniz Experiment with Monistic Pantheism in 1676? (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - "Descartes, Spinoza + Leibniz on Real Distinction, Pluralism, + Monism" (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Draft "Did Leibniz have Pantheistic and Monistic leanings in 1676?" (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Exploring Middle Ground: Was Leibniz's Conception of God ever Spinozistic? (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Expression book (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Finland paper (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Goodin and Kulstad Spain- Gold-Concha (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Hooker's Some difficulities in Leibniz's Theory of Perception (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - History Philososphical Quaretly Reviews (non-review) correspondence (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Italy paper(revised lightly) large print (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - Journal of the History of Philsophy, 1993-01 (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - Journal of the History of Philosophy, 1996-07 (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - Kulstad and Davidson Paper, 2009-10-23-2009-10-24 (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - Locke on Consciousness and Reflection (Box 24, Folder 25)
  - Leibniz, Spinoza, Tsch. paper also Garber comments, 1999-2002 (Box 24, Folder 26)
  - Leibniz's De Summa Rerum Cerisy Sent to France, 1995-10-09 (Box 24, Folder 27)
  - Leibniz- Spinoza on Monism, 18th Century Studies Version (Box 24, Folder 28)
  - Leibniz Review, Monism (Box 24, Folder 29)
  - The Leibniz Review (Box 24, Folder 30)
  - Leibniz, Spinoza, and Tschirnhaus: Multiple Worlds, Possible Worlds (Box 24, Folder 31)
  - Mark Kulstad HO I (Box 24, Folder 32-34)
  - Martine De Gaude Mar Phillipe Hamou Locke et Leibniz (Box 24, Folder 35)
  - New Materialism (Box 24, Folder 36)
  - Monism Force Leibniz Review, 1999-11-19-1999-11-20 (Box 24, Folder 37)
  - MK Diss. Research (Box 24, Folder 38)
  - Pantheism, Harmony, Unity, and Multiplicity! a radical suggestion of Leibniz's De Summa Rerum (Box 24, Folder 39)
  - Philosophical Studies (Box 24, Folder 40)
  - Published Abstracts and some book reviews (Box 24, Folder 41)
  - Philsophy and Phenomenological Research, 1990-06 (Box 24, Folder 42)
  - Reviews of MAK Work (Box 24, Folder 43)
  - Rice University Studies Two Arguments on Petites Perceptions (Box 24, Folder 44)
  - Rezensionen, Nicholas Jolley: Leibniz and Locke: A study of the New Essays on Human Understanding (Box 24, Folder 45)
  - Leibniz's Conception of Expression (Box 24, Folder 46)
  - Roads not taken, short (Box 24, Folder 47)
  - Spinoza Paper HPQ (Box 24, Folder 48)
  - Spinoza Symposium notes, 1977-04 (Box 24, Folder 49)
  - The Southwestern Journal of Philsophy, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 50)
  - Synthese, Two Interpretations of the Pre-established Harmony in the Philosophy of Leibniz, 1993-09 (Box 24, Folder 51)
  - Stuart Brown (Box 24, Folder 52)
  - Studia Leibniz Conception of Expression (Box 24, Folder 53)
  - Tschirhaus,Leibniz + Spinoza (Box 24, Folder 54)
  - SJP: "A Closer look at Leibniz's Alleged Reduction of Relations" (Box 24, Folder 55)
  - Sleigh Anthology (Box 24, Folder 56-58)
  - Young Leibniz final (Box 24, Folder 59)
  - Two arguments about Petities Perception (Box 24, Folder 60)
  - Spindel conference: The Rationalist Conception of Consciousness, 1982 (Box 24, Folder 61)
- Series VII: Addendum (Box 25-28)
  - Departmental
    - Conferences/Meetings for organizations
      - Pre-Mark Kulstad colloquium chair/correspondence, 1964-1973 (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - Pre-Mark Kulstad colloquium/correspondence, 1966-02-14-1968-12-29 (Box 25, Folder 2)
      - Pre-Mark Kulstad colloquium chair/ correspondence, 1967-1973 (Box 25, Folder 3)
        Conditions Governing Access
        This material is restricted please ask archivist for details.
      - Joint colloquium at Rice University, 1975-09-03-1976-03-04 (Box 25, Folder 4)
      - Colloquium speakers, 1976-07-30-1977-02-08 (Box 25, Folder 5)
      - Leibniz symposium correspondence, 1976-03-16-1977-08-26 (Box 25, Folder 6)
      - Leibniz symposium correspondence, 1976-08-26-1977-08-23 (Box 25, Folder 7)
      - Special speakers, Tsanoff lecturer, 1977-06-06-1978-03-13 (Box 25, Folder 8)
      - Foundationalism conference, 1977-06-27-1978-01-16 (Box 25, Folder 9)
      - Mind-Body conference, 1977-06-20-1978-03-29 (Box 25, Folder 10)
      - Justice,equality, and distribution of wealth conference, 1978-05-10-1978-10-30 (Box 25, Folder 11)
      - The phenomenological method conference, 1978-01-16-1978-12-04 (Box 25, Folder 12)
      - Tsanoff speakers, 1978-05-12-1978-11-03 (Box 25, Folder 13)
      - Aristotle's metaphysics, 1978-05-12-1979-03-28 (Box 25, Folder 14)
      - Non-conference speakers,Terry Horgan, 1980-10-06 (Box 25, Folder 15)
      - The relation between epistemology and psychology conference, 1980-11-05-1980-11-07 (Box 25, Folder 16)
      - Nancy Cartwright correspondence, 1981-01-07-1981-01-09 (Box 25, Folder 17)
      - Contemporary utilitarianism conference correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box 25, Folder 18)
      - Realism conference, 1981-11-04-1981-11-06 (Box 25, Folder 19)
      - Future generations and over population Parfit paper, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 20)
      - Derek Parfit speaker at Tsanoff conference, 1982-03-22-1982-03-24 (Box 25, Folder 21)
      - Philosophy of language colloquium, 1983-10-27-1983-10-28 (Box 25, Folder 22)
      - Locke-Leibniz conference, 1982-11 (Box 25, Folder 23)
      - The philosophy of Leibniz and Locke, 1983-11-15-1983-11-16 (Box 25, Folder 24)
      - Colloquia departmental, 1983 (Box 25, Folder 25)
      - Correspondence, 1984-12-10-1985-01-24 (Box 25, Folder 26)
      - Correspondence GTE foundation lecture series on science, technology, and human values, 1985-12-16-1987-04-20 (Box 25, Folder 27)
      - Perception conference, 1985 (Box 25, Folder 28)
      - Glover's lecture circuit, 1986-01-01-1987-01-13 (Box 25, Folder 29)
      - GTE Foundation/ Philosophy correspondence, 1986-05-16-1987-06-29 (Box 25, Folder 30)
        This material is restricted please see archivist for details.
      - Speaker correspondence, 1986-10-03-1987-04-09 (Box 25, Folder 31)
      - Introduction remarks; lecture on bio-medical sciences and human values, 1987-03-23-1987-03-30 (Box 25, Folder 32)
      - MAK chair materials-chair notes on tenure review and to do lists, 1988 (Box 25, Folder 33)
      - Spring conference, 1988 (Box 25, Folder 34)
      - Value theory conference, 1991-1992 (Box 25, Folder 35)
      - Publicity (Box 25, Folder 36)
      - GTE lecture series, current funds (Box 25, Folder 37)
      - Meeting with university council, 1989-01-27 (Box 25, Folder 38)
      - Meeting with social sciences center, 1989-05-09 (Box 25, Folder 39)
      - Cognitive science/epistemology, 1989-1990 (Box 25, Folder 40)
      - Annual events calendar (Box 25, Folder 41)
      - Don Morrison conference "Aristotle in Later Antiquity", 2005-04-15-2005-04-16 (Box 25, Folder 42)
      - Outline of repeatable memos/letters (Box 25, Folder 43)
      - Correspondence,thank you's and conference discussions, 1988-03-17-1990-06-25 (Box 25, Folder 44)
    - Department meetings and agenda's
      - Search committee,salary increases, rejection letters, appointments/hiring, and evaluation. (Box 25, Folder 45)
      - Correspondence about tenure review (Box 25, Folder 46)
      - Departmental correspondence, 1988-07-06-1989-05-10 (Box 25, Folder 47)
      - Chair duties, 1988-1989 (Box 25, Folder 48)
      - End of year meeting department, 1988-1989 (Box 25, Folder 49)
        - Department meeting, 1989-09-06 (Box 25, Folder 50)
      - Department meeting, 1989-12-21 (Box 25, Folder 51)
      - Department meeting, 1990-05-10 (Box 25, Folder 52)
      - Catalog changes (Box 25, Folder 53)
      - Tsanoff + atlas prizes (Box 25, Folder 53)
      - K.brown fund-drive (Box 25, Folder 54)
      - Decisions by Mak as chair (Box 25, Folder 55)
      - Mak chair memorabilia (Box 25, Folder 56)
      - Meetings as chair (Box 25, Folder 57)
      - Recommendation on Sue (Box 26, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence about recommendations, tenure review, and graduate admissions., 1985-09-12-1989-05-02 (Box 26, Folder 2)
      - Departmental correspondence, 1989-1992 (Box 26, Folder 3-4)
    - Philosophy talks
      - Philosophy talks, 1975-1994 (Box 26, Folder 5-9)
    - Publications
      - Bennett volume, 1987-12-07-1990-10-11 (Box 26, Folder 10-20)
        Folder 14,16,19,and 20 are restricted material please see archivist for details.
      - Bennett volume contributions: final form (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Reading group, departmental writings, and annual reports
      - Reading group, 1975-1976 (Box 27, Folder 2)
      - Summer reading group, 1976 (Box 27, Folder 3)
      - Fall reading group, 1976 (Box 27, Folder 4)
      - Summer reading group, 1977 (Box 27, Folder 5)
      - Spring reading group, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 6)
      - Summer long papers, 1990 (Box 27, Folder 7)
      - Fall and spring reading group, 1978-1979 (Box 27, Folder 8)
      - Fall reading group, 1983 (Box 27, Folder 9)
      - Reading group, 1984 (Box 27, Folder 10)
      - Fall reading group, 1984 (Box 27, Folder 11)
      - Fall reading group, 1986 (Box 27, Folder 12)
      - Reading group, 1987-1988 (Box 27, Folder 13)
      - Chaps (Reg.), 1987-1988 (Box 27, Folder 14)
      - Fall reading group, 1988 (Box 27, Folder 15)
      - Fall reading group, 1989 (Box 27, Folder 16)
      - Spring reading group, 1990 (Box 27, Folder 17)
      - Reading group, 1991 (Box 27, Folder 18)
      - Locke reading group (Box 27, Folder 19)
      - Capistran, Locke reading group (Box 27, Folder 20)
      - Plotinus + Locke reading group Summer (Box 27, Folder 21)
      - Departmental writings (Box 27, Folder 22)
      - Unidentified paper (Box 27, Folder 23)
      - Richard Grady (Box 27, Folder 24)
      - Rutherford reading group (Box 27, Folder 25)
      - Departmental writings (Box 27, Folder 26)
      - Annual report file/ faculty reviews (Box 27, Folder 27)
      - Annual reports, 1989-06-30-1992-06-30 (Box 27, Folder 28)
    - Dean and president correspondence
      - Dean correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 27, Folder 29)
      - Dealings with dean Matusow by others (Box 28, Folder 1)
      - Dean correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 28, Folder 2)
      - Dean-related correspondence, 1988-1990 (Box 28, Folder 3)
      - Meeting with dean, 1988-09-01 (Box 28, Folder 4)
      - Meeting with dean, 1988-09-14 (Box 28, Folder 5)
      - Promotion of Larry Temkin, 1988-10-27-1988-11-09 (Box 28, Folder 6)
      - Dean correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 28, Folder 7)
      - Meeting with dean, 1989-03-03 (Box 28, Folder 8)
      - Department meeting, 1989-03-15 (Box 28, Folder 9)
      - Meeting with dean, 1989-03-23 (Box 28, Folder 10)
      - Meeting with dean, 1989-04-10 (Box 28, Folder 11)
      - Dean meeting, 1989-08-31 (Box 28, Folder 12)
      - Meeting with dean, 1990-01-05 (Box 28, Folder 13)
      - Meeting with dean, 1990-03-23 (Box 28, Folder 14)
      - Dean correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 28, Folder 15)
      - Meetings with dean, 1991-1992 (Box 28, Folder 16)
      - Dean correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box 28, Folder 17)
      - Phone conversations with dean or dean's office (Box 28, Folder 18)
      - Review of a student's paper (Box 28, Folder 19)
      - Graduate program promotion (Box 28, Folder 20)
      - Meeting senior faculty morrison, 1989-11-08 (Box 28, Folder 21)
      - Phone president's office (Box 28, Folder 22)
      - Meeting with provost, 1988-09-12 (Box 28, Folder 23)
      - Meeting with provost, 1989-10-10 (Box 28, Folder 24)
      - Correspondence with provost (Box 28, Folder 25)
      - Phone conversations with provost's office (Box 28, Folder 26)
      - Correspondence with the president (Box 28, Folder 27)
        This material is restricted please consult an archivist for details.
      - Christopher Kirwan; Tsanoff lecturer (Box 28, Folder 28)
      - Philosophy of science and campus visits, 1992 (Box 28, Folder 29)
      - Mcclennan packet/ Dean Matusow correspondence (Box 28, Folder 30)
        This material is restricted please see an archivist for details.
      - Future of the philosophy department correspondence (Box 28, Folder 31)
      - Hiring endgame (Box 28, Folder 32)
      - 800 course lists,independent studies, etc. (Box 28, Folder 33)
      - External reviewers (Box 28, Folder 34)
      - Visiting professor (Box 28, Folder 35)
      - Suzanne Borneman's dissertation (Box 28, Folder 36)
      - Notes on admissions to philosophy department (Box 28, Folder 37)
      - Larry Temkin (Box 28, Folder 38)
      - Tsanoff lecturer David Pears (Box 28, Folder 39)
      - Dean of student affairs position (Box 28, Folder 40)
      - H. Tristram Engelhardt reappointment (Box 28, Folder 41)
      - Students: letters/memos, confidential (Box 28, Folder 42)
      - David Pears/ Visiting professor, 1990 (Box 28, Folder 43)
      - Internal reviews on Larry Temkin (Box 28, Folder 44)
      - Larry Temkin's letter to external reviewers (Box 28, Folder 45)
      - Larry Temkin-decision concerning Bowing Green (Box 28, Folder 46)
      - One year appointments (Box 28, Folder 47)
      - External reviews for Larry Temkin (Box 28, Folder 48)
      - University council presentation on Larry Temkin (Box 28, Folder 49)
      - George Sher paper (Box 28, Folder 50)
      - Richard E. Grandy paper (Box 28, Folder 51)
      - Graduate applications endgame (Box 28, Folder 52)
        This material is restricted please archivist for details.
      - Recommendations for teachers and graduate students (Box 28, Folder 53)
      - Recommendations/candidate for Autrey chair (Box 28, Folder 54)
      - Steven Crowell: Tenure process, 1990 (Box 28, Folder 55)
      - Epistemology/cognitive science postion (Box 28, Folder 56)
      - Ethics + Social + Political philosophy tenure track, 1988-1989 (Box 28, Folder 57)
      - Larry Temkin tenure year (Box 28, Folder 58)
      - Larry Temkin (Box 28, Folder 59)
      - Ken water's replacement (Box 28, Folder 60)
      - Larry McCullough (Box 28, Folder 61)